Guide to the William Hillman Shockley Photographs, 1896-1922 and undated, bulk 1897-1909 RL.01177
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Russia: Siberia, 1900; 90 prints
  - Reindeer / Siberia / 25 miles W of Cape Navarin, 1900 July 04 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1547)
    Reindeer crossing river
  - Korak near Anadyr River, 1900 July 04 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1548)
    Two indigenous Koryak women
  - Korak killing Reindeer / at Cape Navarin / 25 m. west, 1900 July 04 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1549)
    Indigenous Koryaks
  - Korak girls skinning reindeer / Siberia, 1900 July 04 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1550)
  - East Cape Siberia, 1900 July 13 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1551)
    Promontory seen from water
  - "Nadjesda" Capt. Friedman's schooner, 1900 July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1552)
  - Nisbet pack train, 1900 August 09 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1553)
    Men and horses
  - Gejiga, 1900 August (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1554)
    View of distant settlement
  - Gejiga, 1900 August (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1555)
    Large group of men, women, children, including Shockley's party, posing in front of log house
  - Gejiga River, 1900 August (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1556)
    Shockley and man in long boat
  - Gejiga, 1900 August (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1557)
    Three young adults posing in front of log house
  - Tungus? at Christovie near Gejiga, 1900 August (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1558)
    Indigenous man standing for portrait near log house
  - Church at Gejiga, 1900 August (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1559)
    Russian Orthodox church and bell tower
  - Gejiga, 1900 August (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1560)
    Cemetery with wooden crosses
  - No known title, 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1561)
    View of wooden houses on hill in Petrapolosk, Kamchatka (from Vanderlip's book caption) with board sidewalk
  - Gejiga, 1900 August (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1562)
    Three young women
  - Gejiga, 1900 August (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1563)
    Group of four girls
  - Christovie's, 1900 August (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1564)
    Shockley's party sitting on ground
  - Christovie near Gejiga, 1900 August (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1565)
    Indigenous man in decorated coat
    From the memoir "In Search of a Siberian Klondike," "Christovie" refers to a camp or trading post site named after a man.
  - Pack Train, 1900 August (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1566)
  - Temporary Camp / Gejiga River, 1900 August 27 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1567)
  - Camp Gejiga River, 1900 August (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1568)
  - Gejiga River, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1569)
  - Camp near Gejiga, 1900 August or September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1570)
  - Christovie Camp, 1900 September 12 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1571)
  - Russian Laborers / Turumcha, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1572)
  - Koreans, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1573.1)
    Laborers
  - Koreans, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1573.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1573.1
  - Turumcha Creek, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1574)
    Pack train crossing river
  - Jahnkovsky / Turumcha Camp, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1575)
    Man astride pack horse
  - Wing dam at Turumcha Creek, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1576)
  - Dead salmon on Turumcha Creek, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1577)
  - Turumcha Creek Camp, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1578)
  - Nisbet giving out vodka / Turumcha Creek, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1579)
  - Camp at Turumcha, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1580)
  - Camp Turumcha, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1581)
  - Russian Boots / Nisbet, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1582)
  - Turumcha Camp, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1583)
  - Nisbet making forge at Turumcha Creek, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1584)
  - Boat / Giliak, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1585)
    Three Nivkh (indigenous people) in dugout
  - Boat of Giliak, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1586)
  - Turumcha, 1900 September (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1977)
    Men in campsite
  - Giliak Tartars at Cape Suffren, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1587)
    Closeup of same Nivkh (indigenous people) in dugout
    Cape Suffren may be the same as Cape Zolotoy, or today, Mys Zolotoy Utës, Eastern Siberia.
  - Reindeer / Cape Navarin, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1588)
  - Near Cape Navarin, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1589)
    Large reindeer herd
  - Bogoraz and Shockley / Anadir River, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1590)
  - Russian trader and wife near Baron Korf Bay, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1591)
  - St. Lawrence Island / Notice distant [?] beaches, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1592)
  - Steamer Corwin / St. Lawrence Island, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1593)
  - Bering Sea, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1594)
    Ship and iceberg
  - Ice / Bering Sea, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1595)
  - No known title, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1596)
    Large city plaza, front of two large buildings with long line of carts and wagons in front
    Location probably Vladivostok: a sign on a building reads: "Briner Kuznetsov & Co.," a major cargp trade and shipping firm in that city (source: Guide to the Great Siberian Railway, 1900)
  - New York, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1597)
    Large ocean liner
  - No known title, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1598)
    Unidentified location; forest with people in distance
    Location and date are uncertain.
  - No known title, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1599)
    View of unidentified settlement nestled in hills
  - Korsakovsk?, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1600)
    View of roofs and church spire of small town
  - Baker's [?] daughter / Saghalien / Korsakovsk, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1601)
    Young woman in garden next to log house
    Writing on back is almost illegible.
- Russia: Bogoslovsk, 1904; 134 prints
  In summer of 1904, Shockley traveled to Bogoslovsk (now Karpinsk), a good-sized city in the Ural Mountains region, photographing along the route a few scenes in Moscow and Perm. Once in Bogoslovsk he documented mining and smelting operations near the city, including iron furnaces, iron ore mines, and alluvial (river) gold mining with dredges as well as smaller manual operations and "starateli" (freehold) workers. Images include city scenes; focusing particularly on a mine manager's house, where he seems to have stayed; Russian families he spent time with; servants; mining students; native costumes and dress; the nearby railroad station; and the roads on the outskirts of the city.
  He spent many months also traveling in the remote country north and east of Bogoslovsk, continuing his documentation of mining operations. Locations include the Lobva, Cackva, and Volga rivers, Verkhotur'e, and Kusva. Along the way he photographed railroad stops, small settlements, lakes, rivers, and travelers in various conveyances on the road. Many of the work scenes in this series also include women laboring as ore sorters and gold miners.
  - Bogoslovsk station, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1603)
    Three young men below a sign prohibiting crossing the train tracks.
  - Bogoslovsk / View from front of company's house, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1604)
    The church in the distance is probably the Cathedral of St. John the Theologian (Vvedenskii Cathedral).
  - House of General Manager / Bogoslovsk Estate / Company House Bogoslovsk, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1605)
  - Bogoslovsk from smelter, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1606)
    View of the city; the church is probably the Cathedral of St. John the Theologian (Vvedenskii Cathedral).
  - Mining students / Bogoslovsk, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1608)
    Two young men in civilian uniforms posing for the camera
  - Bogoslovsk from the lake, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1609)
  - Small Rachette Furnace / Bogoslovsk, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1610)
  - Small Rachette Furnace / Bogoslovsk, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1611)
  - Refining house / Converter house / Bogoslovsk copper smelter, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1612)
  - Bogoslovsk copper smelter, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1613)
  - Bogoslovsk / Goerke and Iron Sows [?] / Copper Smelter, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1614)
    An iron "sow" is a large oblong mass of solidified iron.
  - N. Goerke. Supt. Smelter / Bogoslovsk, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1615)
    Gesturing toward large solidified mass (an iron sow?); notes on back of print and a thumbnail sketch refer to the layers in this solidified mass and read "white metal" and "slag."
  - Pilz Furnaces / Bogoslovsk, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1616.1)
  - Pilz Furnaces / Bogoslovsk, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1616.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1616.1
  - Bogoslovsk / "Starateli" Working Alluvial gold mine, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1617)
    "Starateli" is a name given to free-lance prospectors who often were allowed to take over the diggings of a partially-exhausted placer.
  - Dredge / Bogoslovsk, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1618)
  - Dredge / Bogoslovsk, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1619)
  - Peschanka Gold Placers, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1620)
  - Working Alluvial Gold / Peschanka Placers, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1621)
  - Testing alluvial Peschanka claims / Bogoslovsk, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1622)
  - Peschanka Gold Placers, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1623)
    Includes men on horses
  - Dredge / Bogoslovsk, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1624)
  - Auerbach Iron Mine / Hauling Iron Ore from Bogoslovsk Mines, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1625)
    Man standing behind cart and horse
  - Iron mine / Auerbach/ Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1626)
  - Auerbach Iron Mine / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1627)
  - Auerbach Iron Mine / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1628)
  - Auerbach Iron Mine / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1629)
  - 6' 4" tall / iron ore miner / Auerbach Mine / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1630)
    Russian miner standing in front of horse-drawn cart
  - Auerbach Iron Mine / Woman hauling iron ore / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1631)
  - Bashmakovksy ore sorters, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1632)
    Women workers
  - Ore Sorters Bashmakovsky Mine / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1633)
    Large group of women workers posing outside
  - Ore Sorter Bashmakovsky Mine / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1634)
    Woman pushing cart
  - Bogoslovsk smelter, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1635)
  - Dust chamber / Bogoslovsk Copper Smelter, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1636)
  - Bogoslovsk / Iron Ore ready for burning to soften / Too hard for rock breakers, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1637)
  - Stall [?] roasting / Bogoslovsk Mine, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1638)
    Roasting refers to heating ores or other minerals to very high temperatures to purify the contents.
  - Top of stall / Copper ore / Bogoslovsk Mine, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1639)
  - Bogoslovsk Mine, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1640)
    Chimney emitting smoke
  - At Bogoslovsk Mine, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1641)
    Train at station and three young people in foreground
  - Ore Sorters / Bogoslovsk Mine, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1642)
  - Ore Sorters / Bogoslovsk Mine, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1643)
  - Filling stalls [?] / Bogoslovsk Mine, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1644)
  - Heap roasting copper ore / Bogoslovsk Mine, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1645)
  - Bogoslovsk Mine, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1646)
  - Heap roasting / Bogoslovsk Mine, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1647)
  - Ore Sorters / Bogoslovsk Mine, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1648)
  - "Starateli" working gold placers / Volchanka River / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1649)
  - "Starateli" on the Volchanka River / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1650)
  - "Starateli" pump Volchanka River / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1651)
  - "Starateli" working gold placers / Volchanka River / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1652)
  - "Starateli" working gold placers on Volchanka River / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1653)
    Three women and a man using shovels
  - Station Karayl? Karaool, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1654)
  - Nadesda / Iron furnaces, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1655)
  - Voronsovsky Mine / Man stands on gold ledge which runs to old shaft house / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1656)
  - Roadside shrine near Kooshva Russia, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1657)
  - Near Kooshva, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1658)
  - Woman carrying water near Kooshva, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1659)
    Using a koromyslo
    Koromyslo (traditional beam for carrying two water buckets)
  - House near Kooshva, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1660)
  - Washing gold sands / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1661)
  - W.H. Shockley at Lobva / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1662)
    Sitting in a horse-drawn carriage
  - Lobva near Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1663)
  - "Starateli" working gold placers / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1664)
  - Hut of "Starateli" on Lobva River, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1665)
  - Native dredge Lobva River, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1666)
  - Lobva River, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1667)
    Man crossing shallow ford and another towing a log or boat
  - On the Lobva River / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1668)
    Two men by river
  - Herr Suck washing gold sand / Lobva River, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1669)
  - Gold Mill at Cackva, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1670)
  - Near Cackva / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1671)
    Western man and woman sitting in a troika carriage
  - Gold Mill at Cackva / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1672)
  - Cackva River / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1673)
  - On the Volga River, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1674)
  - Town on Volga, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1675)
  - Anna Stephana on Volga steamer, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1676.1)
  - Anna Stephana on Volga steamer, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1676.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1676.1
  - Town on Volga, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1677)
  - Volga River, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1678)
    Sunset
  - Stage station, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1679)
    Two coaches, one with harnessed horses
  - Water carrier / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1680.1)
    Woman using koromyslo
  - Water carrier / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1680.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1680.1
  - Bogoslovsk, circa 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1681)
    Group of men and women on outing
  - Bogoslovsk, circa 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1682)
  - Ludmilla Petrovna / Katka / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1683)
    Sitting on a bench
    Kalka is the older woman in the portrait.
  - Vanka / Ludmilla Petrovna / Kolka / Bogoslovsk, circa 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1684)
    Kolka and Vanka are names of male youths in portrait.
  - Batka / Katka / Kolka / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1685)
  - Ludmilla Petrovna / W.H. Shockley / Kalka / Bogoslovsk, circa 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1686)
  - Sashka / Katka / Kolka / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1687.1)
  - Yekaterina [Vladimirovna?], 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1687.2)
    Caption seems to conflict with information in first copy.
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1687.1
  - Sashka / Katka / Kolka / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1688)
  - Servants at Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1689.1)
  - Servants at Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1689.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1689.1
  - Servants Bogoslovsk / Janitor and wife, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1690.1)
  - Servants Bogoslovsk / Janitor and wife, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1690.2)
    version of RL01177-P-1690.1, cropped smaller
  - "Anastasia" / Bogoslovsk, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1691)
    Posed photograph of woman servant standing in doorway
  - Mordvinian costume / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1692)
    Young woman (Bobrovsky family) in native costume, standing in large interior room, next to a table with a samovar
    The Mordvins are agragrian people living in the central Volga provinces of Russia
  - Packing up "Bobroffsky", 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1693)
    Two large troikas being packed for trip
  - Bogoslovsk / Departure "Bobrovskys", 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1694)
  - Bobrovskys / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1695)
    Two women in carriage or troika
  - Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1696)
    The same Bobrovsky women in carriage or troika
  - Religious procession / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1697)
    Russian Orthodox procession
  - Religious procession / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1698)
  - W.H. Shockley & Troika, circa 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1699)
  - W.H. Shockley / Troika / Bogoslovsk road, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1700)
  - Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1701)
    Construction of log addition to building
  - Slatts / Bashmakovsky mine, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1702)
  - Kragliascheff / Shockley / Vasili Vasilitch / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1703)
  - Sunset Bogoslovsk / Ural Mts, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1704)
  - Lobchinovsky / Mine Manager / Bogoslovsk, circa 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1705)
  - Lobchinovsky's house / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1706)
  - Mrs. Lobchinovsky, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1707)
  - Lobchinovsky and family, circa 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1708)
    Includes dog
  - Mining Students / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1709)
    Posing in civilian uniforms
  - Mining Students / Bogoslovsk, circa 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1710)
  - Washing gold sands / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1711)
  - Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1712)
    Three girls sitting on log in front of building, backs to camera
  - Getting Water / Bogoslovsk, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1713)
    Filling up a koromyslo
  - No known title, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1714)
    Glacier spilling through rocky pass into lake
  - Ural Boys / Road near Verkheturia, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1715.1)
  - Ural Boys / Road near Verkheturia, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1715.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1715.1
  - Verkhoturia, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1716)
    Town and street with church and spire in background
  - Verkhoturia, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1717)
    Same street, another large church in background
  - Carters in Perm, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1718)
  - Beggar in Perm, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1719)
  - Nijni Novgorod Rwy Station / Moscow, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1720)
  - Children in park / Moscow, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1721)
  - Interior "St. Saviour" / Moscow, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1722)
    Cathedral of Christ the Saviour
  - Villa San Romani / Monte Carlo, 1904 October (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1723)
  - No known title, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1980)
    Bogoslovsk mine, woman worker with cart
  - No known title, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1981)
    Group portrait of women workers at Bogoslovsk mine
  - No known title, probably 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1982)
    Russian upper class family at dining room table
    Same family as in earlier images from Bogoslovsk: man's name is Batka, woman's name is Katka, boy's name is Kolka.
  - No known title, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1983)
    Shockley standing above a worker testing alluvial soils
    Same setting as P-1622.
  - No known title, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1984)
    Architectural details of windows in log home near Kusva
    Same log home as in P-1660.
  - No known title, 1904 September (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1985)
    Family group on outing near Bogoslovsk river
    Same outing as in P-1681 and 1682.
  - No known title, 1904 August (Box 9, Print RL01177-P-1986)
    Log home with shutters
    Same log home as in P-1660 and P-1984.
  - Russia: Bogoslovsk, modern copy prints, 1904, Approximately 130 prints (Box 13)
    These 8x10 inch glossy modern copy prints were created from the original glass plate negatives. With few exceptions, there are corresponding original prints in the main collection series. When there is no original print, the copy print and its entry have been added to the original photographs series and given item-level identifiers. There are 7 such unique images among the modern prints in the Bogoslovsk 1904 series that have been added to the end of the original prints series.
  - Russia: Bogoslovsk, modern copy prints, 1904, Approximately 100 prints (Box 14)
- Russia: Bogoslovsk, 1905; 175 prints
  Returning to Bogoslovsk in 1905, also in late summer and early fall, Shockley seems to have passed through Alaska or Seattle, Washington, visiting Frank Ballaine, a transportation entrepreneur, his brother John Ballaine, and their families, who appear in a set of images in this series. He also photographed several scenes in Moscow, including the university.
  Shockley stayed in Bogoslovsk, again photographing friends and families there, and then traveled very long distances by various means in remote areas of the Urals, passing through Nizhnyaya Tura, and the town of Cheli︠a︡binsk. Along the way he documented railway stations, small settlements, dwellings and their inhabitants, markets, and mining and dredging operations along the Vizhaĭ, Lovza, and Ivdell rivers. There he also photographed indigenous Khanty (Ostiaks), ethnic Tatars, and backcountry hunters and settlers, often in their camps. There are many images of Shockley's own travel party and the troikas, pack animals, and ferries they used in their travels. Only once does he refer to the political instability in Russia, where he documented a large group of railway strikers "discussing situation."
  - Mrs. Goode landlady, 1905 (Box 10, Print RL01177-P-1724)
    Seated in chair, Victorian style interior
  - No known title, 1905 (Box 10, Print RL01177-P-1725)
    Side view of Mrs. Goode, seated in chair, Victorian style interior
    Camera settings written on back.
  - No known title, 1905 (Box 10, Print RL01177-P-1726)
    Western man and woman posing in front of display of dishes with black photographer's backdrop
  - No known title, 1905 (Box 10, Print RL01177-P-1727)
    Mrs. Goode, reading in chair
  - No known title, 1905 (Box 10, Print RL01177-P-1728)
  - No known title, 1905 (Box 10, Print RL01177-P-1729.1)
    Mrs. Goode, standing, posing in Victorian style room